Guide to the Pauline Simington Newcomer Papers, 1950-1994
Department of Special Collections
Pauline Simington Newcomer Papers,
1950-1994
Special Collections M0585
Newcomer, Pauline Simington.
.25 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Gift of Pauline Newcomer, 1991 and 1995.
Biography
American writer; wife of H. Sidney Newcomer, physician, biophysicist and inventor.
Scope and Content
Primarily typescripts of short works, together with some related correspondence.
Access Terms
American literature--20th century.; Newcomer, H. Sidney.
Container List
- Venture to Turkey, 1959-1960. Preface, and related correspondence, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Venture to Turkey, 1959-1960, part I (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Venture to Turkey, 1959-1960, part II (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Venture to Turkey, 1959-1960, part II (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Venture to Turkey, 1959-1960, part II (Box 1, Folder 5)
- The Physick Estate, [c.1957] (Box 1, Folder 6)
- "Old age has no future...," 1970 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- "I have been reviewing...," 1985 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- "Wheaton memories, 1932-1936," 1986 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- "Diary of Pauline Simington, 1932," 1988 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- "How I came to have a plate by Picasso...," 1990 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- The origin of the publication, "A mother's journal for her son, 1887-1908." (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Memories, 1930s and 1940s, with letter, 1991. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Cape May, New Jersey -- memories, n.d., (corrected typescript) (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Clippings re H. Sidney Newcomer, 1979-1988. (Box 1, Folder 7)
- World Trip, 1963, with corrections, 1989. (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Diary, 1932. Reflections, 1988. (Box 1, Folder 9)
- River trip down the Danube from Vienna to the Black Sea, 1968. (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Cape May Memories of the '50s, in Cape May Star & Wave, 7/21/94. (Box 1, Folder 11)